漫威出品
捍卫者联盟
第一季  第六集
原创翻译  双语字幕
最新连载海外影视剧下载
请登陆 www.YYeTs.com
仅供交流学习  禁止商用盈利
翻译     捍卫者联草
翻译     捍奶联盟   杏仁斯嘉丽
校对     捍奶联盟
时间轴     今  大葱
后期     拳拳和马律师的8T
总监     捍奶联盟
人人影视Pro
人人影视官方唯一APP
在线观看，离线缓存，百度云
app.YYeTs.com
官方网站下载 : 人人影视Pro
最新海外影视剧下载
人人影视Pro
人人官方唯一APP
在线观看，离线缓存
-你没事吧  -没事  我是说
- You okay? - Yeah, I mean...
我脑袋还在脖子上
my head's still attached.
-你不用杀了他  -死的不是他就是那孩子
- You didn't have to kill him. - Eh, it was him or the kid.
他们应该能阻止他的
They could've stopped him.
不能冒险  尤其是现在
Couldn't take the chance, especially now.
"尤其是现在"什么意思
What do you mean, "Especially now"?
我们拿到答案了
We got our answer.
他们一直想要杀的就是他
He's what they've been after all along.
是啊  我们早就知道
Yeah, well, we knew that.
我们不知道铁拳是手和会所寻之物的关键[钥匙]We didn't know the Iron Fist was the key to what the Hand seeks.
这个词不是偶然
The word isn't accidental.
你觉得他是关键  他们存活的关键吗
You think he's a key? To what, their survival?
钥匙就说明有锁
A key implies a lock.
-我觉得这是隐喻  -不是的
- I assumed it was a metaphor. - It's not.
你真觉得丹尼能打开什么东西
So you literally think Danny opens something?
而且那东西是值得献出生命的
And that something is worth dying for.
我是武器  不是钥匙
I'm a weapon. I'm not a key.
-不是你所知范围内的钥匙  -我能打开什么
- That you know of. - What could I possibly open?
你说呢  所以他们才还没杀掉你
You tell me. Must be why they haven't killed you.
他们没杀我是因为想让我跟他们同流合污
They haven't killed me because they want me on their side.
铁拳的气是一件武器  千真万确
The Iron Fist's chi is a weapon. That's true.
但我听说  气还有其他用途
But I've heard stories about it being used for more.
封存东西  或者再打开
To seal things shut. Or opening them again.
手和会来纽约是因为他给了他们通道
So the Hand is in New York because he gives them access
或者打开了什么东西
or opens something up?
拜托  伙计们
Come on, guys.
这不可能
That's insane.
你觉得是真是假并不重要
Well, it doesn't matter if you think it's true or not.
他们觉得是真的
It's something they believe is true.
他曾是手和会的一员
He was a member of the Hand.
那是一个充满了撒谎的变态们的组织
An organization formed by lying psychopaths.
他说的话你们一个字都不能信
You can't trust a word he said.
我懂  丹尼
I understand that, Danny,
但我觉得  我们只有一个办法了
but the way I see it, we only have one move.
什么意思
What do you mean?
让铁拳尽可能远离他们
To keep the Iron Fist as far from them as possible.
听起来是很疯狂  但我们没有其他办法了
It sounds crazy, but I don't think we have any other way.
我为战斗献出过生命  你们需要我
I dedicated my life to this fight. You need me.
我们都需要彼此
We all need each other.
这样他们就得逞了
This is exactly how they work.
他们分裂我们  左右我们的思想  削弱我们
They divide us. They get into our heads. They weaken us.
他们让你们质疑信赖的人
They make you question the people you trust.
丹尼  深呼吸  冷静一下
Danny, just take a deep breath and calm down.
别让我冷静  卢克  他们就想这样
Stop telling me to calm down, Luke! This is what they want!
他们想让你们分心  想让你们翻脸攻击我
They want you to be distracted. They want you to turn on me.
索旺达没撒谎
Sowande wasn't lying.
你怎么知道
And how do you know?
他的心跳没变  一下都没变
His heartbeat didn't waver. Not for a second.
他从背后突袭我的时候心跳又怎么样呢
And where was his heartbeat when he came up behind me?
是手和会  你知道他们能控制人
It's the Hand. You know how they can operate.
现在我们知道他们要什么了  他们要你  小子
And now we know what they need. It's you, kid.
棍叟  你要掉进他们的陷阱里了
Stick, you're falling for their trap.
要是亚历山德拉控制了你  这场战争就输了
If Alexandra gets a hold of you, the war's lost.
我不允许那种事发生
I can't allow that.
听着  棍叟  也许我们应该
Listen, Stick, maybe we should just...
让他保持低调  或者
let him lay low, or just...
我们应该把他藏起来
Maybe we should just hide him.
我们没时间了
We're running out of time!
他们在猎杀我们的朋友  家人
They're hunting our friends, our families,
而且他们不会就此罢休
and they're not gonna stop there.
你们听见他说的了  纽约将会变成废墟
You heard what he said. This ends with New York in ruins.
他们不想让我参与
They want me on the sidelines
因为只有我能摧毁他们
'cause I'm the only one who can destroy them.
杰西
Jess?
我们怎么藏他
How do you suggest we hide him?
好吧
Fine.
要是非得这样  我就回去单干
I'll go back to doing this without you if I have to.
我已经失去一座城了  不想再失去一座
I've already lost one city. I'm not losing another.
我也不想
Me neither.
真的吗
Really?
你要强行把我留在这
You're gonna try and keep me here against my will?
我听见你说的了  丹尼  但是
I hear what you're saying, Danny, but...
没人比我更热爱这座城市
And no one loves this city more than I do,
但你不能出这个房间
but you can't leave this room.
随便了
Whatever.
你真想这么做
You sure you want to do this?
我不想  但如果必须的话我会的
No, I don't want to, but if I have to.
就像你隐藏你女朋友的秘密一样
Same way you had to keep your girlfriend secret?
-这事不是过去了吗  -没有
- We're past that. - No, we're not.
丹尼  我们都是一条战线上的
Danny, we're all on the same side here.
感觉可不是
It doesn't feel like it.
-不再是了  -别这么干
- Not anymore. - Don't do this.
你们退后  我是认真的
You guys seriously need to back off.
你待在这  我们保护你安全  好吗
You just stay here. We can keep you safe, all right?
你只需要冷静下来
You just need to calm down.
这就是问题所在  马特
Well, that's the problem, Matt.
我没法冷静
I'm all out of calm.
够了
Enough.
别逼我用这个
Don't make me use this.
对不住了
Sorry about this.
刚出狱  这是个消磨时间的好办法
Nice way to spend your time fresh out of prison.
是啊
Yeah.
真不敢相信要费这么大力气才能再次和你说上话
I can't believe this is what it took for us to talk again.
我不太擅长跟人保持联系  但你可以打电话的
I'm not good at keeping in touch. But you could've called.
好吧
Fair enough.
你觉得这样能绑住他
You think that'll hold?
这是蟒蛇结
Well, it's a constrictor knot.
他越挣扎就系得越紧
Harder he pulls, harder it cinches.
你们不用担心绳子
Rope's not your concern.
要担心的是他的铁拳
I'm gonna assume it's his Fist.
他一发招  什么都阻挡不了
When he summons it, shit goes sideways.
我们有多长时间
How long do we have?
难说  一个小时吧
Hard to say. Eh, maybe an hour.
我们得弄清楚他是什么的钥匙
And we need to figure out what he's the key to.
他们的总部在中城圈
Their headquarters is Midland Circle.
是啊  我们知道了
Yeah, we knew that.
马特  你回去过吗
Matty, you ever go back to that place?
回去  怎么  你之前去过吗
Go back? What, have you been there before?
去过  去年我调查手和会的时候
Yeah. Um, last year, when I was investigating the Hand,
我跟着线索到了一处建筑工地
the, uh, trail led me to a construction site,
现在那里是中城圈了
which is now Midland Circle.
那里有个大洞  数百英尺深
Uh, there was a hole there. Hundreds of feet deep.
就在纽约中央
In the middle of New York?
-是啊  -你这才想起来说吗
- Yeah. - And you're just now remembering this?
你感觉到那洞底有什么吗
You sense anything at the bottom of that hole?
我觉得没有  我一直有留意
I don't think so. I kept tabs on it.
大楼完成后  我也感应不到洞了
Once the building was finished, my sense was the hole was gone.
-你确定  -我对什么事都不能确定了
- You sure? - I'm not sure of anything anymore.
你还没回答她
You didn't answer her question.
怎么才把这事告诉我
How come we are now just hearing about this?
-并不重要  卢克  -再说一次
- It wasn't important, Luke. - Try again.
怎么了  不是  我们要操心的事够多了
What? No. We had enough to worry about.
你有什么瞒着我们
What aren't you telling us?
我当时跟艾丽卡在一起
I was with Elektra.
没把她的事告诉你们是个错误  我知道
It was a mistake not telling you guys about her. I realize that...
你下次再刚巧
The next time you conveniently
忘记了会影响我们其他人的事
forget shit that affects the rest of us...
你也没那么坦诚  杰西卡
You're not exactly an open book yourself, Jessica.
那是什么意思
What is that supposed to mean?
没人在挖掘你的过去
Well, no one's digging into your past.
我的过去不关你的事
My past is none of your goddamn business,
而且也没在努力想杀我们
and it's not actively trying to kill us.
-时间不多了  -如果我们想要更多答案
- Clock is ticking. - So if we need more answers,
回中城圈是唯一的办法
going back to Midland Circle is the only play.
我们上次都勉强逃出来
We barely made it out last time,
他们肯定会有所准备的
and they're gonna be waiting for us.
-她说得对  -那我们怎么找到他能打开的东西
- Yeah, she's right. - So how do we find whatever he opens?
建筑师
The architect?
我客户的丈夫  你女朋友想杀的那个
My client's husband. The one your girlfriend tried to kill.
他设计了那里
He designed the place.
你觉得他知道丹尼跟这一切的联系
What, you think he knows how Danny ties into this?
值得一试
It's worth a shot.
那你俩快去吧
Well, I guess you two better get going.
你呢
What about you?
得有人留下看着他
Somebody's gotta stay and watch him.
最好是能经得住拳头的
Preferably somebody who can take a punch.
我知道你醒着
I know you're awake.
是啊
Yes, I am.
你睡了好几个小时了
You've been sleeping for hours.
谢谢
Thank you.
我喜欢这里
I like it here.
回纽约来
Back in New York?
不
No.
回到你身边
Back with you.
缅怀艾丽卡·纳齐丝
上帝将抹去他们眼角的泪水  将再没有死亡和悲伤  没有哭泣和痛苦  因为曾经已经逝去  启示录  21:4
纽约市  圣徒公墓
-丹尼还昏着呢  -很好
- Well, Danny's still knocked out. - Good.
追踪这些混蛋这么多年
You know, after years of tracking these assholes,
听说他们干的各种混蛋事
you hear about all the shit they've done.
就算你干掉了他们  他们死了
And even after you take 'em off the count and they're dead...
晚上依然夜不能寐
it's still enough to keep you up at night.
这混蛋你在哪找到的
Where'd you find this piece of shit?
151街和阿姆斯特丹街的仓库
Warehouse on 151st and Amsterdam.
他在哈莱姆招募孩子
He was hiring kids out of Harlem.
利用他们做清理队
Using them as a cleanup crew.
销毁唐人街一家仓库里的尸体
Destroying bodies at an abandoned warehouse in Chinatown.
我们的总部  那些尸体是我们最后的成员
Our headquarters. Those bodies were the last of us.
看着那孩子  我来处理这个
Watch the kid. I'll take care of this.
你什么意思
What do you mean, take care of it?
不管这是不是跟手和会有关  这都是凶杀
I mean, Hand-related or not, that was a homicide, man.
你又说对了  你知道得越少越好
You are right again. Less you know, the better.
你要干什么  处理掉尸体吗
What are you gonna do, get rid of the body?
是啊  差不多吧
Yeah. Something like that.
没错
Yeah, you're right.
我知道的越少越好
Less I know, the better.
你要不要告诉我一个无偿案律师
So you wanna tell me how a pro bono lawyer
怎么能在纽约住得起这样的阁楼
can afford a loft like this in New York City?
你现在看不出
You can't tell now,
但街对面有块大霓虹灯广告牌
but there's a neon billboard across the street.
大部分人晚上会睡不着
Keeps most people up at night...
但我不会
not me.
懂了
Got it.
而且  我偶尔会帮助房东
Plus, I occasionally help the landlord out.
虽然我不引以为豪  但我会穿上紧身衣
Not proud of it, but I put on the suit
去收拾那些迟交租金的人
and rough up people late on rent.
希望你是开玩笑
I hope that's a joke.
抱歉这么乱
Sorry about the mess.
没事  我家才叫乱呢
It's all right. You should see my place.
你在家工作吗
What, do you work from home?
我以前有个合伙人  我们有间办公室
I used to have a partner. We had an office.
后来呢
And?
现在没了
Now we don't.
准备好了吗
You ready?
嗯
Yeah.
一切都好吗
Everything okay?
嗯  没事
Yeah. Uh, yeah.
走吧
Let's go.
一个特工在索旺达的一间仓库里发现了这个
An operative discovered this at one of Sowande's warehouses.
无疑是我们的老朋友棍叟送去的
Delivered, no doubt, by our old friend Stick.
索旺达自我们离开昆仑就一直跟我们在一起
Sowande has been with us since we departed K'un- Lun.
他的离去会震动组织上下
His loss will be felt throughout our entire organization.
已经发生了
It has happened.
死亡就是这个样子
This is what mortality looks like.
-这是本可以避免的  -是他自己失手被擒
- A loss we could have prevented. - He got himself captured.
-我们根本没去找过他  -得了
- We didn't even try to find him. - Oh, please.
-我们就别假装为他的死难过了  -假装
- Let's not pretend to mourn this loss. - Pretend?
难道我们在一起的这些年一直和和睦睦吗
As if our time together has always been peaceful.
难道我们就没发生过分歧吗
As if there's never been any discord.
难道我们没有成功躲过这屋里
As if we haven't all survived assassination attempts
站在我们对面的人派来的刺客吗
by those across from us in this very room.
现在  我们更该团结一致
Now, more than ever, it's time to show unity.
我们本来是团结的
We were unified.
直到你把黑空带来
Until you brought the Black Sky into the fold.
她在哪
Where is she?
-她很安全  -那是什么意思
- She's safe. - What does that mean?
我不觉得我没必要回答你
I don't think I have to answer to you.
但鉴于这几小时内发生的事
But considering the events of the last few hours,
我觉得最好还是把她隔离起来
I thought it best to keep her isolated.
因为你怕我们杀了她
Because you think we will kill her?
不
No.
我觉得如果她感到了你的不忠  可能会杀了你
I think she might kill you if she even senses your disloyalty.
我们无意不忠
We mean no disloyalty.
我们的目标是一致的  几世纪以来一直如此
Our goals are in alignment, as they have been for centuries.
我现在不太确定了
I am not so sure anymore.
我们必须为索旺达的牺牲坚持战斗
We must honor Sowande by continuing to fight for
来纪念他失去的东西
what he lost.
生命本身
Life itself.
我们的领袖已带我们走到了今天
Our leader has brought us this far.
我愿意继续追随她
And I for one will continue to follow her,
直到我们抓到铁拳
until we have the Iron Fist.
直到我们从纽约得到我们需要的东西
Until we get what we need from New York.
我觉得是在前面
I think it's up here.
-你觉得  -我不知道
- You think? - I don't know.
这些豪宅看上去都一个样  是吧
All these brownstones look the same, don't they?
该死
Oh, shit.
抱歉  总忘记你是...
Sorry, I keep forgetting you're...
没事  经常的
Don't worry about it. Happens.
那么  我需要了解这个建筑师的什么情况
So, what do I need to know about the architect?
他妻子雇我找他
His wife hired me to find him.
他没跟她说多少
He didn't tell her much.
当然不会说什么纽约地下有秘密隧道
Especially not about some secret tunnel under New York.
不是隧道  是个洞  直上直下的
Not a tunnel. It's a hole, straight down.
是啊  他自己爆头之前
Right. Well, right before he shot himself,
他说"他们"要毁掉整座城市
he said "they" were going to take down the city.
显然  我们知道"他们"是手和会
Obviously, we know now "they" are the Hand.
-他也是一员吗  -他说他是好人
- Was he one of them? - He said he was one of the good guys.
你相信他吗
And you believed him?
我不会听心跳  但我会看人
I don't read heartbeats, but I do read people.
他都急疯了  开始囤积炸药
He was desperate. He started stockpiling explosives.
你觉得他的目标是中城圈
And you think his target was Midland Circle?
或许吧  其实  好像就是这里了
Maybe. Actually, I think this is it.
-好像  -99%确定
- You think? - Ninety-nine percent.
92%吧  那也不少了
Ninety-two percent. But that's still a lot.
-莱克西  是吧  -我妈妈不在
- Lexi, right? - My mom isn't here.
你知道她什么时候能回来吗
You have any idea when she'll be back?
你想干什么
What do you want?
-就是聊聊  -又聊我爸爸吗
- Just to talk. - About my dad again?
关于发生的事
About what happened.
你自己说了  他卷入了黑帮还是什么的
You said so yourself. He got mixed up with the mob or something.
-不是黑帮  -抱歉  你是谁
- Wasn't the mob. - Sorry. Who are you?
-他是个律师  -什么
- He's a lawyer. - A what?
莱克西  我叫马修·默多克
Lexi, my name is Matthew Murdock.
我们认为你爸的事没那么简单
We think there's more to your dad's story.
如果你能回答几个问题
If you could just answer a couple of questions,
会帮我们大忙
it'd be a tremendous help.
好吧
Okay.
关着的门以前是有一定含义的
Closed door used to mean something.
抱歉
My apologies.
我们认识那么久了
In all the time we've known each other,
我从未见过你这样
I've never seen you like this.
你的位置拥有很大权力
Your position is one of great power.
但这即是福气也是负担
But it is a burden as much as a blessing.
所以我说服了其他人追随你
Which is why I've convinced the others to follow your lead.
你和我一直能理解彼此
You and I have always understood each other.
有一个条件
Under a single condition.
我们要自己去找到并抓到铁拳
We will seek out and capture the Iron Fist ourselves
不用黑空
without the Black Sky.
这么没有信心不像你
It's not like you to show such a lack of faith.
亚历山德拉  你一般也不会如此...
And it's not like you, Alexandra, to show such...
软弱吗
Weakness?
我们的兄弟们  虽然不会说话  但说的是事实
Our brothers, while clumsy in delivery, speak the truth.
黑空一直是你的预言  你的愿景
The Black Sky has always been your prophecy, your vision.
-而你失败了  -我不同意
- And you have failed. - I don't agree.
她对我们的成功很重要  你得跟他们谈谈
She is essential to our success. You must talk to them.
我试过了
I've tried.
她复活之后  我们并未更接近抓到铁拳
Ever since her resurrection, we are no closer to the Iron Fist,
找到圣物  或回归昆仑
or the substance, or returning to K'un- Lun.
我们只是离死亡更近了
The only thing we're closer to is death.
你怎么看不到我看到的
How can you not see what I see?
她是很厉害
Oh, she is skilled, yes...
我不是在说她的能力
I'm not talking about her abilities.
她拥有的力量  只有你我能想象
She has a strength that you and I can only imagine.
就算是  其他人不这么认为
Even if I did, the others do not feel the same way.
其他人想要我的位置
The others want my seat at the table.
如你所说  这以前也发生过  我也经历了
As you said, it has happened before. I was there.
高  当初就是你带头的
Gao, you were the one who led it.
过去都过去了
Past is the past.
现在  我可能是你唯一的同盟
Right now, I may be your only ally.
你不相信黑空足以拯救我们
And you don't believe the Black Sky is enough to save us?
我已经知道不该相信任何东西
I have learned not to believe in anything.
但我们在一起的日子还没结束
But our time together is not over.
现在还没
Not yet.
考虑下我的提议吧
Consider my proposal.
我们今晚就可以准备行动
We could be ready to move tonight.
你是对的
You were right.
你挣开之后  我就在这里
I'll be right here when you're done.
你把我像个囚犯一样捆着
You've got me tied up like a prisoner.
不是"像"  你就是个囚犯
Not "like." You're definitely a prisoner.
看上去并不好
It's not a good look.
马特呢  杰西卡呢
Where's Matt? Where's Jessica?
他们去挖掘中城圈的情报了
They're digging up info on Midland Circle.
我们认为一切都是从那里开始
We think that's where it all started.
"我们"  你们几个都要一起对付我吗
"We"? As in the rest of you who worked against me?
听着
Look.
如果你肯听我们的  而不是跟我们打
If you'd listened instead of fighting us,
你就也能参与我们的讨论了
you would've been around for the conversation.
而且我觉得你也会认同的
And I think you would've agreed.
中城圈有蹊跷  尤其现在我们知道了那个洞
Midland Circle's suspect. Especially now that we found the hole.
什么洞
What hole?
默多克觉得中城圈有点不对劲
Murdock thinks there's something weird about Midland Circle.
他们让你看住我
And they got you on guard duty.
那得看你了
Nah, that depends on you.
大错误
Big mistake.
你看不懂情况吗
Don't you see what's happening?
你把我捆了起来  就好像我是敌人
You've got me tied up like I'm the enemy,
而他们在外面  想杀死我们在乎的人
and they're out there trying to kill the people we care about.
-米丝蒂在保护大家  -暂时的
- Misty's keeping everyone safe. - For now.
但我所在乎的人
But I care about a lot more people
一个警察局里放不下
than we can fit in a police station.
我知道你也一样
And I know you do, too.
城市有危险
This city is at stake.
我和你
Me and you...
卢克·凯奇和铁拳
Luke Cage and the Iron Fist...
我们该出去战斗
we belong out there.
携手站在最前线
Together, on the front lines.
听着
Look,
我不喜欢打仗
I don't like to fight.
但如果非打不可  我会采取聪明的策略
But if I have to do it, I do it smart.
把我关起来不叫聪明
Locking me up is not smart.
跟三个与你同一阵线的人打也不怎么聪明
Neither is fighting three people that happen to be on your side.
等我可以重汇聚我的气了
The moment I can refocus my chi,
我就会挣脱这把椅子
I'm getting out of this chair.
我等着
I'll be waiting.
他在干什么
What's he doing?
冥想
Meditating.
...吧
I think.
他说什么
He said something about
仙鹤式  集中他的动物
crane pose and centering his animal.
然后我就没听了
Then I tuned him out.
是灵
Anima.
-什么  -他在集中他的灵
- What? - He's centering his anima.
好吧  我对那些神秘的玩意不感兴趣
Mmm, sure. Uh, I'm not into that mystic stuff.
不是"神秘的玩意"
It's not "mystic stuff."
只是另一种世界观
It's just a different way of viewing the world.
-大不相同  -是啊
- Quite different. - Yeah.
是视角
It's about perspective.
你再跟我说一遍
Hey, why don't you tell me again
你是怎么打了一条龙  得到了你的神奇拳头
about how you punched the dragon and got your magic hand?
在寿老的最后试炼中
During the final trial of Shou-Lao the Undying,
-我将拳头打进了他炽热的心脏中  -哥们
I plunged my fist into his molten heart. - Dude,
我开玩笑的
I was kidding.
炽热的心脏
Molten heart, huh?
肯定很疼吧
I bet that must've hurt.
是啊
Yeah.
你无法想象
Like you wouldn't believe.
我有次正面挨了一记火箭筒发射的炮弹
I took a direct hit from a rocket launcher once.
还曾被一把猎枪打中头
Got blasted in the face with a shotgun.
是杰西卡干的
By Jessica.
我们那个杰西卡
Our Jessica?
相信我  我宁可去面对龙
Trust me, I'd face a dragon over
也不想招惹杰西卡·琼斯
Jessica Jones any day.
你来之间发生了什么
What happened between you two?
我们有过一段
We had a moment.
但我们都不得不走上不同的道路  所以
But we both had to go on our different paths, so we...
不同的道路
Different paths?
你说话越来越像我了
You know, you're starting to sound like me.
我不知道你们觉得能发现什么  很简单的
I don't know what you think you're gonna find. It's simple.
我爸抛弃了我们  丢了性命
My dad abandoned us and got himself killed.
-我知道可能不好理解  -并不是的
- I know it's probably hard to understand... - Actually, it's not.
你爸并没想伤害你  或你妈
Your dad didn't wanna hurt you or your mom.
她现在每晚都哭着入睡  所以
Yeah, well, she cries herself to sleep every night now. So...
莱克西  你爸在家里设办公室了吗
Lexi, did your dad have an office in the house?
没有  他分开工作和生活  对他有什么好处
No, he... he kept work and life separate. Some good that did him.
莱克西  你让我想起了我的一个朋友
You know, Lexi, you remind me of a friend of mine.
他爸爸是个拳击手
His dad was a boxer...
他不自量力结果送了性命
who got in way over his head and got himself killed.
很久以来
And for a long time,
我朋友也以为他爸爸抛弃了他
my friend thought his dad abandoned him, too.
直到有一天  他得知了真相
Until one day, he learned the truth,
他爸爸被杀
that his dad was actually killed
正是因为他不想再犯罪了
because he wanted to stop being a criminal.
因为他希望儿子能为他骄傲
Because he wanted his son to be proud of him.
不管怎样  我是想说
Whatever. I'm just trying to say
我朋友的爸爸是个好人
that my friend's dad was a good guy
或许你爸爸也是
and maybe yours was, too.
她叫艾丽卡·纳齐丝
Her name was Elektra Natchios.
你不是她
You are not her.
你远超出曾经的她
You are much more than she ever was.
有个男人
There was a man.
被人称为地狱厨房的恶魔
They call him the Devil of Hell's Kitchen.
在那段人生里  他让艾丽卡死了
And in this other life, he let Elektra die.
他是我在战斗中碰到的那个吗
Is he the one I faced in battle?
他或许会再次企图欺骗你  让你背弃我们
He may try to deceive you again and turn you away from us.
他不会得逞的
That won't happen.
你还应该知道件事
There's something else you should know.
关于我的事
Something about me.
我要死了
I'm dying.
你不能死  手和会永生不死
You cannot die. The Hand lives forever.
我们希望能
We want to.
但就连我们的身体也是有极限的
But even our bodies have always had limits.
当没有外力带来死亡
And when death doesn't come from outside forces...
有时生命体也会自我了断
sometimes the organism tries to end itself.
我需要  一件圣物
The thing I need is a substance
我们最初在昆仑发现了它
that we first discovered at K'un- Lun.
多年来  它一直让我们死而复生
And for years, it served to bring us back from death.
我为复活你  用尽了它
I used the last of it to bring you back to life.
为什么
Why?
因为我知道你会是我们的救赎
Because I knew you would be our salvation.
当我看到你
And then seeing you,
我意识到  这么久以来
I realized that after all this time,
虽然有其他人相伴
and even with the others at my side...
我受够了孤独
I was tired of being alone.
如果我们不找到更多这种圣物
If we don't find more of this substance,
我们都会死
we'll both die?
是的
Yes.
你得确保那不会发生
You need to make sure that doesn't happen.
你是黑空
You are the Black Sky.
等这一切结束  你和我  我们两个
And when this is over, you and I, the two of us...
将永远效力于生命本身
Will serve life. Always.
你的心率在下降
Your heart rate is slowing down.
呼吸
Breathing.
可以产生好气
That's how good chi is born...
排出体内的坏气
and bad chi is expelled from the body.
比那要复杂一点
It's a little more complicated than that.
也没复杂多少
Not by much.
其他人我不难想象
You know, from the others, I could've expected this.
但你是最该理解的
But you of all people should understand.
我们在打仗
We are at war.
赢得这场战争是我们的责任
And winning that war is our duty.
打仗或许是  但赢
Fighting it, maybe. But winning it...
会需要别的
is gonna take something else.
-你是跟训练了我的那些长老受训的吗  -不是
- You trained with the same elders I did? - No.
那你为什么认为把我绑起来是正确的选择
Then what makes you think tying me up is the right choice?
你似乎是走一步想一步
It seems like you're just making this up as you go along.
的确  孩子
I am, kid.
幸存者都这样
That's what survivors do.
老实说  我都不知道该从何说起
To be honest, I don't even know where to start.
从头说
Start at the beginning.
我爸爸  是那种人
My dad was... was one of those guys...
他特别和气  简直无聊
He was so nice, it was boring.
-后来呢  -他就变了
- And then? - Uh, and then he changed.
他工作更多了  那并不奇怪  但是...
He worked more, which... which wasn't that weird, but...
但是然后他不睡觉了
But then he stopped sleeping.
我晚上可以听到他走来走去
I could hear him at night, pacing down here.
他也不和我们吃饭了
He stopped eating with us.
他不吃饭  不排泄
He stopped eating, period.
他有时会坐在钢琴前  但他不弹
He'd sit at the piano sometimes, but he wouldn't play.
不像他以前一样
Not like he used to.
他和他以前完全不一样了
He didn't do anything like he used to.
我很想他
I missed him.
在我妈妈找你之前很久的他
Long before my mom came to you.
他去世前很久的他
Long before he died.
-你弹吗  -什么
- Do you play? - Excuse me?
-钢琴  -不弹  你呢
- The piano. - Uh, no. You?
我会  我小时候在教堂学了一点
Uh, yeah. I learned a little in church, growing up.
-哥们  你干什么  -我...可以吗
- Dude, what are you doing? - Just... Do you mind?
-就在前面  -这边吗
- Oh, it's straight ahead. - Here?
是的
Yeah.
我弹得不是很好  但是...
Uh, I wasn't very good, but...
-我们该走了  -给我一点时间
- Come on, we should go. - Just give me a second here.
你听到了吗
You hear that?
D调
D-sharp.
琴槌磨到了什么
The hammer's ruffling something
再敲下来的  这边
before it hits the string here. Here.
那是什么
Whoa, what are those?
好像是你爸爸建造的大楼规划图
Looks like the plans to the building your dad was working on.
在钢琴里
In the piano?
他不想让它落入坏人手中
He didn't want them to get into the wrong hands.
你们是...好人吗
And yours... the right ones?
莱克西  我保证  不管你爸爸在做什么
Lexi, I promise, whatever your dad was doing,
我们跟你是同一阵营的
we're on your side now.
但是我们需要点时间  好吗
But we're gonna need a minute here, okay?
他的确是想炸掉它
He was gonna blow it up for sure.
-该死  -怎么了
- Oh, shit. - What?
这不是大楼的
This isn't for the building.
不  这是别的
No, this is something else.
这是大楼下面的东西
This is something below the building.
-那个洞  -不
- The hole? - No.
不管这是什么  肯定是在洞底
Whatever this is, it's at the bottom of the hole.
中城圈下面藏着东西
There's something under Midland Circle.
-你感觉怎么样  -非常好
- How you feeling? - Never better.
但你和那孩子现在可算不上一条战线
But you and the kid ain't drinking buddies.
别被他哄得放松警惕了
Don't let him get your guard down.
他只是很沮丧
He's frustrated, that's all.
是吗  再给他点时间  他能把我们俩都干掉
Yeah? Give him a second, he'll take us both out.
他也是这么说的
Yeah, so he said.
我听那个女孩说你刚出狱
I heard the girl say you were fresh out of prison.
怎么了
Yeah?
-那已经是过去的事了  -不
- That's behind me now. - No, it's not.
从来不是
Never is. Not really.
不管你按下多少次拳头
No matter how many punches you pull.
什么意思
What's that supposed to mean?
意思是一旦出事
That means when the shit hits the fan,
你放纵自己的话就会造成更多破坏
you could do a lot more damage if you let yourself go.
我不是来破坏的
I'm not here to do damage.
我不会以看别人受伤为乐
I take no joy in watching people get hurt.
我是来寻找答案的而已
I'm here for answers. That's it.
我也曾进过监狱
I was in the joint, too.
那是在我与手和会交战之前
Before I went to war with the Hand.
十年前  那时候我还是个孩子
When I was a kid. Ten years.
一个瞎子进了监狱  很有意思
That was a lot of fun, being blind on the inside.
然后我遇到了那些教我如何真正战斗的人
Then I met these people who taught me how to fight for real.
教我这个世界真正模样的人
Taught me how the world works for real.
我出狱后  就有了目标
When I got out, I had purpose.
这些人  就是你所谓真纯会的人
These people, these the ones you call the Chaste?
是的
Yeah.
对我来说最接近家人的人
Closest I ever had to family.
除了马特
Aside from Matty.
和艾丽卡之外
And Elektra.
-节哀顺变  -谢谢
- Sorry for your loss. - Thanks.
这和我们接下来要做的事相比不算什么
It's nothin' compared to what comes next.
这香是用来干什么的
What's with the incense?
能帮助我冥想
Helps me meditate.
寻求指引
Ask for guidance.
宽恕  之类的东西
Forgiveness. That kinda thing.
那个建筑师发现自己的大楼下还有一个建筑结构
So the architect discovers a structure underneath his building.
不管那是什么  他都宁死
And whatever it is, it's bad enough
也要炸掉那个东西
that he dies trying to blow it up.
没错  他想摧毁掉
Right, he wanted to destroy it.
但他不想炸掉
But he didn't want to blow it up.
我觉得他是想压倒那个结构
I think he wanted to collapse it down.
你确定那个洞里的结构是人造的吗
Are you sure the structure in the hole is man-made?
会不会是什么基岩
Could it be some sort of bedrock?
三十层楼深  还有完美的圆顶
Thirty stories deep, in a perfect dome?
好吧  有道理
All right. Fair enough.
杰西卡
Jessica?
你怎么知道的
How'd you know?
知道什么
About what?
我爸爸的事
About my dad.
格斗瞎眼律师
A crime-fighting blind lawyer,
我猜背后的故事肯定很精彩
I figured there had gotta be a good story there.
或者很糟心
Or a shitty one.
你接手了我的案子  我也赠与回礼
You took my case, I took yours.
我只是觉得如果我们相互信任
I just think we'll work better together
会合作的更好  你觉得呢
if we trust each other. Don't you?
这是你对我说过态度最好的话
That is the nicest thing you've ever said to me.
可别习惯这种语气了
Yeah, don't get used to it.
这么多烟
So much smoke.
这是什么东西
What is this stuff?
加点这个  加点那个
Eh, little of this, little of that.
那孩子没说错
Kid was right.
这是战争
This is war.
他们需要他才能胜利
And they need him to win it.
假设我们只有两种选择
We assumed we only had two choices.
逃跑或者引战
Run or fight.
我找到了第三种
I found a third option.
有点不对劲
Something's wrong.
卢克  卢克
Luke! Luke!
你不会感觉到任何痛苦的  孩子  我保证
You won't feel any pain, kid. I promise.
你没必要这么做
You don't have to do this.
亚历山德拉说我不知道你是什么  她没说错
Alexandra said I didn't know what you were. She was right.
你是我们的武器  但他们将你据为己有
You were our weapon. But they made you theirs.
你在说什么
What are you talking about?
你一直全心全意为昆仑效力
You served K'un-Lun as well as you could.
如果有幸  你会再次见到那里
With any luck, you'll see it again.
我想那里肯定很美
I would imagine it's beautiful.
棍叟
Stick...
你得听我说
you need to listen to me.
我也想有别的办法  孩子
I wish there was another way, kid.
但这个世界上有很多东西比我要坏的多
But there are things in this world far worse than me.
棍叟
Stick!
你不能夺走她  孩子
You can't have him, girl.
你没法再向我发号施令了
You no longer get to tell me what to do.
艾丽卡
Elektra!
-听我说  -马修
- Listen to me. - Matthew.
你不需要这样做的  好吗
You don't have to do this. All right?
你不属于他们  你不是那样的人
You don't belong to them. This is not who you are.
见到你真好
It's good to see you.
不
No!
我能和你一起吗
May I join you?
我知道你喜欢一个人用餐
You like to dine alone, I know.
但我觉得我需要做出弥补
But I feel the need to make amends.
我还以为那些酒
I thought that entire vintage
都在马赛大火中付之一炬了
had been destroyed in the fires at Marseille.
巴利阿里群岛海底总能让你
You'd be surprised what you can find
发现不少惊喜
at the bottom of the Balearic Sea.
继续说
Go on.
我本来是不想和你一起离开昆仑的
I did not originally want to leave K'un-Lun with you.
你还记得吗
Do you remember?
我记得  你想和长老们一起
I do. You wanted to stay with the elders.
你想
You wanted to...
只用我们的发现做善事
use our discoveries only for good.
你该知道真相了
It's time for you to know the truth.
我当时不想留在昆仑
I did not want to stay in K'un-Lun at the time.
我只是不想和你一起走
I simply did not want to leave with you.
这并不意外
Well, that's no surprise.
你一直只关注你自己的力量
Your own strength was always your singular focus.
所以我才活到现在
It's gotten me this far.
我还在等你给我道歉
I'm still waiting for my apology.
你应该和高聊过了
I assume you've spoken to Gao.
是的
I have.
不管之前发生了什么
Regardless of what has come before,
这次我们都应该一起战斗
we were meant to fight this war together.
当然了  所以...
Of course. Which is why...
我希望你能好好享用这最后一顿饭
I wanted your last meal to be a good one.
你一个人来...
You came alone...
挑战我
to face me?
愚蠢
Foolish.
但你一直是...一头孤狼
But then you always were... A lone wolf.
这个比喻很有意思
An interesting metaphor.
但是如果你了解我
But if you knew me at all...
你就会知道
you'd know...
我是猎狼者
I hunt the wolf.
如果你了解我
If you knew me at all,
你就会知道  我永远会赢
you'd know I always win.
在会议室
In the boardroom...
兰德先生  我代表大家
Mr. Rand, I know I speak for all of us
告诉你  我们很高兴又和你一起了
when I say how nice it is to have you with us again.
这次  是永远一起了
This time, for good.
这场战争
This war...
没有结束
it isn't over.
战争的关键是
Well, the thing about war is...
只有两边都坚信自己是正确的才会发生
it only works if both sides believe they're the good guys.
你要打倒我们  你要夺回曾是我们的东西
You fight to defeat us. We fight to get back what was once ours.
你想要什么
And what is it that you want?
回到昆仑
To return to K'un-Lun.
那不可能  那里已经被你摧毁了
That's impossible. You destroyed it.
我看到了
I saw.
你看到了你想看到的东西
You saw what you wanted to see.
事实上  我们俩没有什么区别
The truth is, you and I, we're not so different.
我们拥有共同的家
We share the same home.
我们都只想回到那里
We both want nothing more than to return to it.
现在  没有了死亡的阻碍
And now, without death standing in our way,
我相信我们能合作
I believe we can, together.
不
No.
我们不一样
We are not the same.
我知道
I know.
但是最终
But in the end...
现在就是最终
and this is the end...
你会像其他所有人为我做的一样
you'll do what everyone else does for me.
你会效忠于我
You'll serve.
你要带我去哪里
Where are you taking me?
解决了他  我们可以继续我们的计划了
Well, now that he's taken care of, we can proceed as planned.
计划进展得并不顺利
Little has gone as planned.
我们是抓到了铁拳  但是代价呢
Yes, we have the Iron Fist, but at what cost?
有什么代价能比我们的命更重要
Is any cost too great for our survival?
如果是我们的命  那的确没错
When it's the life of one of ours, yes.
我们必须放眼未来
We must look to the future.
那是我们最重要的资产
It's our greatest asset.
从现在开始
From this moment forth,
我们唯一的重点就是保护圣物
our sole focus is to secure the substance.
在他的盟友来找他之前
Before his allies come for him.
我们不能小看他们
We cannot underestimate them.
不要小看我
Do not underestimate me!
杀了卢克·凯奇
Kill Luke Cage.
杀了杰西卡·琼斯
Kill Jessica Jones.
还有地狱厨房的恶魔  不管他是谁
And the Devil of Hell's Kitchen, whoever he is.
很高兴你们都赞同实行计划
I'm so happy you're all on board with the plan.
但是别忘了  是我消灭了我们的敌人
But let me remind you, I neutralized our enemies.
是我抓来了铁拳
I brought you the Iron Fist.
你们只会制造混乱和冲突
I was able to keep the most important operation
是我得以确保
in our history running
能继续实行我们最重要的计划
while you succumbed to chaos and conflict.
我已经证明我是唯一真正的领导者
I have proven myself to be the one and only true leader--
他的名字叫马修
His name is Matthew.
我的名字
And my name...
叫艾丽卡·纳齐丝
is Elektra Natchios.
你们现在都效忠于我了
You work for me now.
有问题吗
Any questions?